

Omer Kamal Ali Ebead

Date of birth: 14/06/1998 | **Nationality:** Sudanese | **Phone number:**

(+249) 118912916 (Mobile) | **Email address:** omerebead1998@gmail.com

Whatsapp Messenger: 00249118912916

Address: 11111, Khartoum, Sudan (Home)

ABOUT ME

A motivated and Proactive Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in creating and executing innovative software solutions to enhance business productivity. Highly experienced in software development lifecycle. Also, I have a first class degree in Electrical and electronic engineering from university of Khartoum and I was one of the best 100 student in Sudan in high school Exams. Interested in Computer Science field which I find very helpful in solving today's problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/11/2022 - 01/08/2023 Khartoum, Sudan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AMUNDATA

- Full-stack developer using reactis and flask py
- Business intelligence using Power bi
- developing and maintaining Arab organization for agricultural development Platform

Website https://www.linkedin.com/company/amundata

01/05/2022 - 01/11/2022 Khartoum, Sudan

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER OROOMA

- Frontend developer using reactis
- Backend developer using nodejs
- Full-stack developer using MERN stack and Kotlin

Website https://orooma.com

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/01/2015 - 01/01/2021 Khartoum, Sudan

BACHELOR DEGREE IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING University of Khartoum

Website https://uofk.academia.edu/ | Final grade 8.14

01/01/2012 - 01/01/2015 Khartoum, Sudan

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA Al Mashaail High School

Final grade 93.9

DIGITAL SKILLS

Software development

Git | REST API management | DBMS: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server | Flutter (basic) | MERN Stack (MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS) | Flutter Basic Skills | kotlin Programming | Python

Graphic Design and UI/UX

Figma & Adobe XD | Adobe: Photoshop, Illsutrator, Lightroom

Data Analysis

Power BI Power Query

Machine learning

Computer Vision | Deep Learning frameworks: PyTorch,Tensorflow,Keras

Other Skills

Microsoft Office package: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access | Arduino, Microcontrollers

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

01/10/2018 - 15/10/2018 - South Africa

Deep learning Indaba. The Deep Learning Indaba is the annual meeting of the African machine learning and AI community with the mission to Strengthen African AI.

Link https://deeplearningindaba.com/2023/

PROJECTS

01/11/2022 - CURRENT

Arab organization for agricultural development Platform Developing a platform for Arab organization for agricultural development.

01/10/2021 - 01/04/2022

Temporal Analysis of Regional Sustainability Using CNNs and Satellite Data Using computer vision and satellite imagery to classify LULC and also to calculate Biocapacity and test the model in Sudan Satellite images.

REFERENCES

Hiba Hassan Sayed Mohamed Ali

- Deputy dean of Faculty of engineering, University of Khartoum.
- Hiba_im@hotmail.com

Anas Showk

- Associate Professor
- Electrical and Electronic Engineering Department, Faculty of Engineering, University of Khartoum.
- · anas.showk@uofk.ed
- 00249155664062

Amal Elsamani Ahmed Taha

- Lecturer at the University of Khartoum
- University of Oxford, M.Sc., 2022
- Istanbul Technical University, M.Sc., 2017
- · amalelsamaniahmedtaha@gmail.com
- · amal.elsamani@uofk.edu
- 00249912221881

Omer Hamdi

- CEO of AMUNDATA.
- · omer@amundata.com

Mohamed Satti

- · CEO of OROOMA.
- · m.satti@orooma.com.